then you may be able to delete the lower
channel and only provide the password to
the five team or that's a good idea
I'm like Hello all right let's get this
show on the road we have tons and tons
of updates to give probably one that's
uppermost and everyone's mind was did
the burn on schedule for the 15th
happened and it didn't happen on the
15th it happened on the 17th that's
because I was blindsided by a an issue
but it did happen on the 17th I don't
know about 6:00 6:00 in the morning
so 129 million rocks were burned and the
transaction has been recorded
I think Edie posted a link in Skype if
not we can post that to announcements so
so as as per our promise to the
community with respect to the redemption
process that that piece is completed and
so every every obligation that I am
aware of has has been met so thank you
thank you all and now it's time for us
to execute any other any comments or
questions about that before we move on
to UM other fun stuff
I did I didn't want to queue up a
discussion about the staking token
supply in the future um okay yeah but
let's let's just do it since Ron tokens
why don't we go go with the flow so what
did you wanna how did you and talk about
that oh okay um yeah hi everyone I I've
been talking to a number of investors
over the last several weeks and a few of
them in particular are asking about the
future supply of revs or other staking
tokens and Greg and I went through one
iteration that we I think covered even
last week during this hangout but there
remain to be some some outstanding
questions so uh Paula paste paste the
link of where this where we're
documenting the intentions and then I'll
also share my screen and the questions
are about you know from from an investor
or you know other stakeholder in rocks
you know several of us in the on the
call are getting some of our pay in
rocks is a and rocks will convert one to
one to rev at the time that our chain
launches so that much is clear to people
but there's other questions and that's
what I'd like to go through and from an
investor's perspective you know whether
it be you know some of us holding rocks
personally or in someone buying equity
in the holding company and the holding
company owns RIT rocks so they want to
make sure that those are um going to
remain protected is who how do they know
that you know more revs won't be issued
after the go-live or more other staking
tokens won't be issued and that
essentially changed the percentage what
compute power and investment they have
in the future so let me share the screen
that's that that's the context for this
um yeah so and some of you might might
be a better to look at the link I pasted
here but so a lot of these there's
there's no controversy but mainly it's
about the supplier but we'll also cover
some of the things that Greg mentioned
post burn so question one there's a
million rocks although some are now on
spendable channels I'm sorry a billion I
always got those computer just kidding
um no additional rocks will be created
the contract addresses here you see all
the transactions number four and I've
updated this distribution after after
the burn so still with the coop is about
eighty six point two percent and and
then the rest is either with Holdings or
in hands um and then number five well
any rocks be burned to just supply and
Greg as mentioned 129 some million rocks
were burned no other burn are planned
number five six is about the amp
proceeds we're a Greg feel free to
comment on that but that's really not
what I wanted to cover yeah let's just
let's stay on topic for now Savin what's
you know what's the what's the budget
you know probably need some work in the
the budgeting area but that that kind of
has to be discussed
I think internally first and we really
haven't talked too much specifically
about the budget either from but but the
I know easy
Greg and others too navneet and I helped
with this on staffing forecasts which is
the primary driver of budget schedule
you know we're we're running a little
bit behind on closing the Series a
and getting that lined up so there's a
possibility this may move into early q4
because this q3 of 2018 estimate was
based on closing and q3 let's see then
this is the big question we might may
need to split this into several I'm not
going to read through all of 9 but you
know or maybe I should will there be
other native economic tokens and so we
eventually say yes there may be rocks
will convert to Rev on a one-on-one
basis we get above we distinguish taking
oaken's versus other economic tokens
like similar DRC 20 tokens on ethereum
and then if the state keen tokens were
to be added what would be its logistic
rate relative to Rev and we verify this
last week that revs will always have a
[Music]
ten to one advantage over others and so
we clarified the languages you know in
terms of the total supply of revs versus
the total supply of other staking tokens
um that that the total would still be
ten times better or kind of the tenth of
four if when you when you do the math of
the each each individual token so there
there there remains these outstanding
questions I have in comments here I'll
paste the this into the document is so
those following along can see it for the
mean time so right before 11 I'm pasting
some questions I'd like to answer
interactively here Oh
which are now beginning with you know
what will be the total supply of Rev so
will it be you know 1 billion minus
the whatever number burned was great
Greg you there yes so I was just saying
goodbye to Natasha saying sagen yeah so
you know the Oh some of the open
questions that are in my mind that would
help address the investors questions is
you know what's the total supply of Rev
is it just what's converted or are there
going to be more revs
created at conversion time um so we
haven't we haven't talked about the the
initial Genesis block well what are the
things that makes I mean you know I'm
perfectly fine with with that supply
amount that's perfectly reasonable um
one of the things that makes the the
whole issuance question complex is
because um even even existing
cryptocurrency protocols have issuance
as a part of the validation or mining
solution so what we can talk about is an
asymptotic cap on total supply um but
but making that language very precise is
um is is harder because yes there is if
we take a sort of traditional it's a
funny funny word in there in a field as
old as 2008 um and if we take the
traditional approach there there is a
kind of issuance that happens and so
know the total supply isn't capped it
depends upon how you look at the supply
if you look at the supply at the end you
know the well I can't get above a
certain amount so it's capped but is
there more to be issued yeah there's
more to be issued so so but that's
that's a small amount and it's
asymptotically decreasing the issuance
is decreasing um so so that's kind of
the the what makes it a little bit more
subtle but for all intents and purposes
we can treat it as if the supply is
capped and and that's I think a
reasonable assumption uh moving forward
I don't see any any real reason
at the current state - - you know
contemplate issuing a lot of a lot more
token yeah you you part of that
explanation I think is the design of
Casper and validators would be that some
revs will or other staking tokens would
be created
you know fiat style um at that at that
time and yeah that that was a new
concept to me a couple weeks ago and
they've been obvious to others but I I
thought that during the betting cycle
since there's bonding and there's fees
coming in through the the transactions
that all of that would be distributed
among the miners and and additional revs
wouldn't be required could you elaborate
why um
the protocol requires additional reps to
be created um it's not that it requires
it's just that it makes some of the
maths work out a little better if you're
trying to optimize for if you're trying
to optimize for certain things so it's
it's not it's not a hard fast
requirement I think actually blad favors
a fixed total supply while Vitalik um
favors
issuance I certainly know that that's
what it's your name is planning so uh
sooner that we get that we go with the
issuance thing yeah question is is the
effective cap two billion or is it 1.1
billion
or is it ten billion yeah but that's
that's a great question and that's
currently what we don't have designed
right I mean that's a that's a not a
knob or a dial that were course we're
still calculating with I mean my my
druthers currently is that you know it's
about 1.1 billion um but but but that
depends what what impacts that is the
longevity of the protocol right
so that's but but you know that that's
odd is about 1.1 billion is the total
cap you know I think some of the X there
is that you know feel like it could be
arbitrary in my view is yeah we know the
details of the mining and the asset
density probe the consensus program a
protocol and the Egyptian and Noah all
have not been finalized yet and to
finalize the cap before those are
finalized seems to be unwise to some
extent in my view and I also feel that
the stakeholders the members of the
co-operative want some ability to
consent to the decisions and I think you
know we if cooperative does own the
tokens and as that that as that ability
to met the decisions as they are made
absolutely agree with you Jim on every
point first of all you know if you any
party that wishes to be involved in in
that part of the discussion they should
join the co-op um and and and and and
engage with the membership and talk to
the board I absolutely agree that's kind
of the whole point of the cooperative
structure and I think that you're right
that the you know the wisdom is very
clear here let's not let's not commit
ourselves prematurely um especially if
it's gonna screw the whole protocol
later because we just don't have the
Headroom uh you know it's like what what
with it when you try and do sound for a
show you got to leave yourself a little
Headroom and this is the same the same
is true here we got to leave ourselves a
little Headroom if especially if we
expect
and intend on the the network to to be
lasting the next 50-100 years which is
entirely possible so so these these are
the kinds of things that we have to be
thinking about and and why it takes a
little bit of time to come to I mean
gosh darn it I mean just just
negotiating a single safe has taken us
weeks right and that's a really small
number of details by comparison the
total number of details that we're
considering when we're considering the
design of these protocols so yeah if it
takes a little time I think that's
alright but that's why there is some
subtlety here with respect to cap
purchase issuance
you
then answer your question ed I know it
was a long winded one
you
I was on mute yes I was and I and I
appreciate your points Jim as well I
think what we should do is you know
state that this is the intent I don't
really want to hamstring our oxygens
here but uh and you know the investors
need some assurance about effectively
that the preference that revs will have
and continue to have and that they won't
get you know their value will be diluted
significantly yeah yeah I mean it's like
it's that going to be it's not going to
be a multiple greater than um - right
the the if I if I remember if I remember
the calculations you know it should be
you know less than one the multiple less
that one I wish add it to the supply
okay so that's not what I just wrote I
wrote if it would be that's like oh
that's 1/10 right that's what that's
exactly in compliance right so oh I said
a multiple okay I misunderstood of what
a multiple one I thought would mean a
hundred percent a less than one so some
percentage less than a hundred percent
should be the total of the total
additional supply created by issuance
okay but yeah you're you're saying a no
more than two billion or an additional 1
billion of what I wrote a hundred
million yeah right but that it's likely
to if I have my druthers and we can make
it all work out then it would be you
know a 1/10 it just it what it means
does it the you know the curve has a
certain shape right over time so it's
shallower and shallower up at the top
end
okay but so they you agree that the
estimate total supply I would approach
1.1 billion that's that's if I have my
druthers but we have to we have to you
know mess about with this and see so
he's saying he would like it to be
around 1.1 he is pretty certain that it
won't be higher than 2 it's definitely
not going to be 10 yeah anything look it
will always decrease and it's officially
yeah the issue and the issuance keeps
decreasing right but you haven't
thinking about what that means in terms
of future validators right it's motive
it motivates you to get in the game
early but but but what's your
motivations later on yeah yeah okay um
will the supply of revs be capped and
I'll say yes see above or reword that
okay will validators be paid from the
current supply stay ketones or will
newsday we answered that earlier a
different way okay
I think this will help a lot great we'll
talk about this particular investor
offline yeah but I think this addresses
their major concerns um we also had
other topics in here about Lozano just
that one more about list on exchange
which really wasn't uh what I intended
to talk about today um any other
questions from the from the audience
community maybe is a better word from
those present yes
okay awesome so my intention is you know
I'll review the wording for precision it
is probably all good renumber this and
asked the cooperative board members to
endorse this as an intention thankfully
thank you no thank you for driving that
discussion it um so um all of that
discussion actually depends directly
upon the development that we're doing
and we so we have some nice updates
Kenter you in a place where you in a
chat about what we've been doing let
this past week sure thing so yeah I got
some news I guess um the the cell one
contract is now running on rosette and
so uh just to give a bit of an overview
on what that exactly means um let me
just share my screen see does everyone
see my screen yes I can okay cool so let
me get out the screenshot that uh Greg
posted I think two weeks ago but um so I
think it was actually two weeks ago when
the cell on contract
what's compiling from rolling to rosette
here and so this is essentially the top
half of it was done but now I guess this
week's news is that the bottom half of
the cell on contract is complete and so
what we see here is this is essentially
yeah pardon I was I just actually
finished this last night but um working
all mine anyways uh so this these
I guess I guess six lines are basically
the sell one contract and um just just
to give an easier parse let me start
from the very the rolling contract side
so essentially there's two methods in
the sell contract there is a getter and
a setter and then the getter just
receives the state and then the setter
just some sets the state and so here
um when that compiles down to rosette we
you see that in the form of two blocks
or um one is the this block for the gap
and this block for the set and yeah so
if we just um let me just give a demo on
the fact that this are so the idea here
is that it's very similar to the the
hello world rbl contract that um I ran
through a Bowie ball so two weeks ago
somewhere around that time frame but we
are creating a new namespace we're
defining the sell contract itself we
define a printer for it and then we
invoke the sell contract and we send it
the state first and then we just get the
state and then the printer is already
listening on the channel that the get
returns to and so it will just print
that out and so in theory like copy and
then let me just switch over to be pinch
so this is this is rosette and if if I
just copy and paste what um I just
showed you the sell contract
printer and then actually getting the
state then yeah I'm sorry that's a whole
bunch of debugging output but the the
important part here is that it actually
prints out the state that I passed in um
believe I can find it around here um
French um partially filled yeah um
yes we can skip that until I clean up
the debugging output but this there is a
state output here somewhere in this I'm
debugging statements so yeah I mean
there there is basically there's that
cleanup to do and but it should be
mostly through and you know the hello
world works as before and also the hello
world hello world produce first and
really from the UM I use from the
milestone perspective you know the the
big news is the cell one contract down
but really um the I guess the the
technological is more technical
milestone news is that like the the
consume and produce now take multiple
channels and this is essentially what
allows the the cell one contract to
actually run and I'm not going to dive
into too much of the details there but
um everything will be on space dot RB l
if you're interested and um the idea is
that before the consume only took um one
channel at a time so to speak but now it
takes multiple and there's a whole bunch
of logic that is related to that fact
and you know get it I guess really
sorting through all that is at the core
of this double-spaced implementation so
I don't know I I'm glad I was able to
get through that and I there's going to
be a lot of testing but um I think
that's the update for now yep that was
just amazing thank you very much I just
wanted to say that that was it's been a
real joy to work on this stuff this is
this is why I get up in the morning one
of the reasons anyway
and I really really enjoyed being able
to chat with you about that and about
kind of the subtleties of the
implementation um we will be running
some more detailed tutorials about the
subtleties of the implementation because
people should be aware of them on the
one hand there's a lot more power here
than we're talking about or even that's
exposed well in the in the surface
language on the other hand there's
there's some natural trade-offs that we
believe coincide with this sort the same
sorts of trade-offs you find in the
physical world so for example we will be
sent we synthesize the the sort of multi
that the the what can get a high
dimensional state machine um when you
have a complicated joints so we
synthesize that we try to do a good job
of making an efficient state machine the
state machine is implicit in the data
structure that the temple space
structure that Kent is talking about and
so what people will notice is if they do
very very fancy joint logic we will we
will provide the correct state machine
however um it will not run very fast the
the more come the more complicated your
joins are the more complicated joint
patterns are the the slower your code
will run and so and it's very very
unlikely that most people really need um
super-complicated join joint patterns in
their protocols most of them will end up
being much simpler and so they can write
those by hand rather than synthesize the
full state machine and this is exactly
the same as you find in chemistry so
referring back to the physical world
yes it is possible for in different
particles to converge on each other and
have and have dynamics that are
associated with in party interactions
however the dominant the statistically
dominant what likelihood is is that only
to the particles interact which is why
most of chemistry is written down in
terms of you know two-party interactions
so so you know is exactly the same kind
of trade-offs the same kind of
cost-benefit sorts of things that show
up here there there's a lot more that
goes on there as well so one of the
things that that we want to point out is
that the code is set up now for the
content delivery layer so the rolling
surface area does not currently provide
the content delivery semantics however
the underlying substrate is ready for
the content delivery mechanism that we
had in Special K so this is so we're
already you know sort of busting of the
seams in the sense of spilling well pad
you know the work that's been done
spills well past milestone 1 and into
milestones 3 and 4 and it just turns in
and this is kind of the way software
development happens like if you have a
good design then often you're you're
nailing down solutions to problems that
are are far in the future very early in
the game if you do it well another
another thing I want to point out is the
the opportunity for optimizations so let
me just do a quick screen share well
before you go there I just have a quick
question for Kent so
you said that this was doing the bottom
half of the diagram did you have to make
changes to the rosette VM in order to
compile the rbl to rosette opcodes
yes no to be specific um it's not
exactly the bottom half of the diagram
but there's there's actually to answer
your question first no there's no
changes needed to arm the rosettes
implementation I just had to add a bunch
of helper methods to the RBL library so
to speak you know stuff like couple
append and a few other double related
methods but um but what I meant
um earlier when it's not strictly the
bottom half is that well it actually
kind of goes past it in the sense that
it actually executes the byte code and
we're seeing the results of it and it's
you know in the in when this goes
through the whole pipeline we're just
planning to store the byte code I'm sure
you know this but uh just just making it
clear - yeah I guess the rest
yeah I mean to amplify Kent's statements
so the compiler has always assumed a
target of the rosette VM augmented with
a run time and the run time is precisely
the tupple space together with you know
access to the store when we when we make
distributed access to the storage layer
and access to the the comp layer alright
thanks for that yeah and so that run
time is as part of that and and and what
Kent has done is to flesh out the tuples
face piece of that um to include not
only the semantics necessary for rolling
with the semantics necessary for the
much broader content delivery mechanism
um so and then uh so then moving on to
this this looking specifically at the
contract that Kent was looking this is a
not sure if this is cell 1 or cell 2 but
they're closely related so let me just
zoom in here so people can see see an
example of the contract so this was the
contract here I'll just change the color
so you can see let me do text color and
then make that red okay so that that
part is what Kent was working on and and
got running even at this version or cell
wall I don't remember if this is so or
not but the important point is that
state is the parameter to this con
contract and as a result in this sort of
naive compilation strategy um this gets
mapped on to a channel in the tupple
space however if you were to wrap on
this contract in a new so you can make
an outer level contract right as you
wrap this contract in a new that makes
state a private channel right then the
compiler can see you never sinned State
out here so it remains private to this
this region and and that in fact no
other party can see state and so state
can be mapped not on to a channel in the
tuples face but to a logo there and so
this is how we do optimization um that
will make this thing move at a quite a
reasonable speed right if every single
variable every single local buried last
be mapped onto a channel in the temple
space this will be very slow but the
reality is that you can you can see just
through textual analysis through static
analysis when you have situations where
you can take channels like state here
and map them onto things like local
variables and that's going to be the
means by which we we get this up to two
you know a high performance
general-purpose programming language and
that's that's the aim is that rolling
becomes a high-performance
general-purpose programming language so
so so all of this to me is a strong
indication of the sort of this synergy
of all the the architectural pieces and
then the now we're starting to see some
of the benefits of that the mathematics
is providing to us ok so moving on I
just noticed that that Lisa I just saw
you Lisa you joined us I'd like to
introduce Lisa rice I don't know if
we've introduced her on the Hangout
before but welcome I think you're I
think you're muted Lisa
yes I was muted so thanks for the
introduction and it's nice to meet
everybody I tried to join earlier um but
I couldn't get my phone to work properly
but now I'm all stuck on the laptop so
um I'm really glad to be part of the
group awesome so I just wanted to let
everyone know so Lisa and I have a
agreed that she'll be coming on in the
role of acting CFO for the coop
she was already acting CFO for Holdings
um and it is doing such great job she's
expanding her role and responsibilities
responsibilities and just so we're
having some regular meetings now um as a
part of expanding the role that HJ and
at least a play and taking over or
getting some of the business stuff off
my plate and Lisa and Ed and I met and
did some fairly extensive staffing
forecasting and we hope to make that
make that public so people can see a
very you know in a detailed manner the
way in which the coop is spending its
resources when it comes to staffing um
and then will likewise do do similar
things for other operational
expenditures um but it's really great to
have Lisa on board and to have more and
more people getting involved in in just
you know executing the the business of
being the coop so I'm very excited
thanks for joining thank you
um all right so let's see um what are
some of the other updates
Mike and I are scrambling to get a
couple of papers in we just discovered
there was some deadlines for for a
couple of venues where we think we might
have a shot but the deadline is Friday
Mike you want to talk about what we're
what writing and where we're submitting
- sure one of the conference's is on
metamodeling
we may have mentioned k-frame work with
four on these hangouts but it's a it's a
platform for developing languages and
giving them formal semantics as you
develop them now rolling and Rosetta of
course already have formal semantics but
this is a nice way of quickly building
an interpreter for language but our main
interest in it is that once we've got a
que description of the language we can
then implement our ladle algorithm on K
and take a que description of rolling or
any other term calculus and produce a
que description of a typed version of
that language that uses our behavioral
spatial typing come constructions so
that's our intent we spoke with Gregory
yesterday and we're going to continue
working with him on that
so the first paper then is reporting on
using graph enriched levere theories as
kind of a toy Kincaid framework that has
very nice categorical semantics and then
explaining ladle as acts on these in
which live ear theories I'm sure we'll
get into gnarly details when we try and
do it on K but this will at least get
the point across and we'll run have
easily understood semantics the other
paper is for express SOS and expresses a
conference about the expressivity of
different languages particularly
concurrent languages and so we're
writing up a paper on how reflection
that's the are enrolling and real
calculus
gives you expressive abilities that you
don't have without it so we're excited
to try and communicate this to a
receptive audience
yeah well well said I just want to
elaborate a little bit on what you said
about Kay framework so um Mike and I are
at the point now where we're beginning
to prototype the ladle algorithm itself
as opposed to just the specific instance
of the ladle algorithm as relates to
rolling um and so we have been looking
at different platforms for where to
where to do the the the sorry I'm a
little strikes on presentation of ladle
yeah I'm just I don't understand why my
camera isn't showing up oh because I
have a camera on let me see anyway I'll
try to I'll try to fix this next time um
no oh wait hang on one second I might
have it here Vidia
doesn't offer anything else okay well I
don't know I don't know why it's not not
working
but anyway so so we've looked at several
[Music]
will do will do Mike thanks um so so
we've looked at several different
options so there there are there's a
bunch of trade offs right so the trade
offs have to do with maturity of the
automated formal proofs platform versus
the you know the ability to take the
artifacts that we produce there and
connect them to what we the code we put
in production so for example if we were
to use Isabelle Hall or more talk it's
quite unlikely that the artifacts
produced there would have direct links
to the artifacts that we put into
production and that raises this this
trust gap where we have to go okay you
know and then a miracle occurs and the
code that's in production is somehow
related to the code that we prove
correct then we want to minimize that as
much as possible
so Kay framework is quite interesting in
this regard because it's written that
the academic version is now completely
rewritten in Scala so that's quite
interesting all and it has much of the
properties that would be that we want um
it's different in structure from the
commercial version which is not used by
let's see Boeing Toyota NASA and other
other major firms on large code bases on
to to catch bugs um there it's that's
largely about the the the execution so
they they even though parts of it are
written in scala and parts are written
in java on the backend target for the
through the execution is oh camel so
that's kind of interesting and
apparently that's 10,000 times faster
than the academic version so it's very
very interesting result but you can't do
a lot of the things that you can do with
the academic version currently our aim
is moe
to prototype the ladle algorithm itself
and and then as a as the byproduct of
that effort get a be able to run that on
the a particular cave framework spec
brulee and thereby get automated proof
so the soundness and completeness also
emphasize the output of K framework is
an interpreter but because K framework
is general enough to encompass types it
can also serve as a type checker so we
are not proposing that we use K
framework to generate a roland compiler
but rather to generate a type checker
that we can then integrate and use as
column exactly right um and so so one of
the things that we did yesterday was we
spoke with the principle of K framework
Grigor a row suit who's at Illinois um
and he's got a he's got a research team
um there at Illinois and he's also got a
team on the commercial side of the K
framework operation uh he seemed very
excited he felt that we were doing
exactly the right thing by beginning
with the formal semantics and and
progressively hardening that formal
semantics which is what we're doing um
so that was that was encouraging to get
you know to get that kind of feedback he
also seemed quite excited about
supporting us so he said that if there
were features of K framework that either
needed to be refreshed or updated or
even developed whole cloth um that he
would be open to that sort of thing so
that's that's also good news because it
means you know that we have people
around a platform who you know the
platform is being actively maintained
and enriched and developed and and
they're receptive to our are our
interests so so that's it that's a very
good thing it's also eager to have it
integrated into other tools like say
IntelliJ
exactly so that was that was the other
thing that I'm thinking a lot about is
making sure that there's a path not only
for rolling but for late the ladle
algorithm itself into commercial tools
um so one of the things that I want to
be doing over the next several years is
working with tool vendors like IntelliJ
and Eclipse and and other major tool
vendors NetBeans for example and making
it and making possible that they can
participate in this this next generation
of software development tools if we get
I mean that ultimately as I've tried to
suggest it would be delightful
if the compiled chain as an example from
a contract source code all the way down
to executing byte code could be
facilitated through the blockchain
of course that's going to require a
bootstrap but if that's the case then
tool vendors can participate in the
economic the paradigm shift is happening
with with the blockchain which i think
is a very very good thing so we're kind
of laying the groundwork for all of that
um so so and then the flip side is not
so much not just that they will be
responsive to us but also that we're
talking about an algorithm that
significantly enriches enhances the
value of K framework itself so K
framework gives you this ability to you
know take a formal spec and generate an
interpreter and on the academic side
symbolic execution and those kinds of
things which allow you to to reason
about in an automated fashion about your
program what it doesn't do is to
generate the type system well what we
let the ladle algorithm needs at a
minimum is a spec of the the determined
calculus the the language or the virtual
machine which is the kind of thing that
you would supply to K framework and then
in addition we need a
a formalization or specification of the
collection that you want the results a
captured in and so when you add that to
the K framework spec then you can use
ladle to generate the type system and
then again just just as an aside to so
that people can see this is a much
broader scope than we were talking about
once you have that kind of capability
you can turn it into a database engine
so all the code that's that is related
or generated in a language like rolling
for which you have this kind of type
system you can search a repository using
those types and the search algorithm is
directly related to on the semantics of
the type checker so so this is how the
next generation of tools can can provide
a unprecedented level of value for for
applications so that's that's why we're
very excited to work with grigory and
the K framework folks so I feel like
it's a very important step towards
realizing some of the co-op's goals and
some of holding schools ok that was a
big long deep update let's see anything
else let's leave it open for for
questions now we've got about 10 minutes
and and see if there's community
engagement to other people who want to
speak yeah let's just leave it open
one thing that I had been thinking about
was just introducing some of our guys
Grif McClellan has been hired to work
with us he is possibly going to work on
the storage layer with you Tim shrila is
has just joined us this week and he'll
be working on translating with the
expression hierarchy and in the rosette
VM as a starter project and we've also
got Chris Kirkwood watts coming on later
he'll be working on the comms layer and
we're looking at continuing hiring so
more and more people getting involved
with with the effort to implement the VM
in Scala this is awesome this is really
good
I was super I mean one of the things
that Mike and I spoke about is that the
Kant has made so much progress that very
soon like in two or three weeks the the
VM reimplementation is going to be the
major blocking a task because we need to
have that in place before we integrate
the storage and the cause and the
storage encom's can continue but before
we sort of connect everything of the
reimplementation to the VM is is going
to be a dependency that needs to be at a
certain stage of completion so um this
is great to get the the right kinds of
folks in there and getting them working
on that um is it still the intention
that you know with some restriction the
the C++ rosette will work with storage
in comm the shit there should be no
there should be no reason why it won't
how
the one big caveat there is that once we
have the sort of bite for bite
reimplementation or bug for bug
reimplementation
I will be mucking about with the
delimited with the continuation
semantics
so the continuations will be more in
alignment with delimited continuations
rather than the rosette one-shot
continuations that significantly extends
our feature range for the next
foreseeable you know you know at least
out 5 or 10 years so with the c++ I have
no plans to upgrade the way the
continuations are handled so that will
you know fall farther and farther behind
we this week we released a the arcane
explainer video which is on the YouTube
channel and the coop and the dot IO
sites yay and we're getting closer to a
very clear a branding document colors
and sort of character a sort of feel of
the space as well
very good that's awesome can you paste a
link in the chat uh yeah I'll find that
our Jane co-op
yeah just our Kane co-op yeah that's
does the link okay probably comment you
they had to put this on our chain
comment and but before I had a chance to
say anything it was our up there almost
immediately fantastic yeah I wanna yeah
I want to thank Nathan and the animator
as well the I think given a pretty
limited budget and uh and my insistence
on getting it done they did a great job
this this won't necessarily be the last
video and the you know that we we
welcome feedback on it in whatever
whatever form and also you know what
additional videos you'd like to see yeah
and also I wanted to I wanted to say
that we finally a closed where we
reached consensus I think from from the
stakeholders who were the noisiest and
and most attentive to the issue on the
the name of the staking token or the
first staking token and that will be Rev
um and if there are collisions on
exchanges if please correct me if I get
this wrong it'll be re Vivi on for
letter exchanges and rvv on three letter
exchanges is that is that correct did I
get that right everyone
and Nathan I could live with that I
don't I think the exchanges might be
part of that decision to write but right
yeah things like that yeah but that was
the the UM did the agreement that we
reached right there's your nose finally
q what does it what did you say
oh yeah yeah I was just making sure yeah
it'll be re VV at least at the moment
but we have to sort of be in that
discussion right and then I think ad has
already um it has has already reserved
Rev token calm so so we're you know sort
of shoring up all of the all the
intellectual property you know um domain
registration that kind of thing around
it um so I'm just excited you know
Revis Reb is the name also under the
circumstances since there's a lot of
advances going on maybe I can pair up
with maybe Joe or can't and do some news
jacking on the I cos that have been
issuing like we can we can kind of
analyze a lot of the problems that are
going on or and and see how our platform
would fix it oh yeah absolutely for sure
now that's that's exactly what we want
to do for sure yep yep um cool so these
are I mean I did the pace at which we
are moving is incredible I also want to
say next week Alex
Balkan coin fund will be out as well as
Joseph and we'll be working in detail on
the ROE Lange tutorial um and we're all
teed up thanks to Kent's efforts were
all teed up to
to have a lot of the examples that we're
producing BX Cuba so in particular the
cell contracts are prototypical wallets
so that's that's very very exciting for
us I will be traveling from July 1st
through July 15th I will be still be on
the hangouts but headed off to Berlin to
do a little bit of development
recruiting um and oh because we were
flying Iceland air we're going to be
stopping over in Reykjavik for a couple
of days but I will be available and um
sorry Vlad is here in Seattle and he's
pinging me he wants to get some lunch um
so so I'm a little bit distracted
um but yeah so that that's kind of some
of the upcoming stuff um I should
probably get back to Vlad so is there
anything else that we we want to talk
about before I disappear I just wanted
to mention briefly I put a link in the
chat for the token factory search that
Sh requires a three-letter token for a
theory of tokens our ROC is available um
I think we you should get it registered
there they have some pretty nice trading
interfaces and things that you know
being registered now puts you up there
on the makes the rock more accessible oh
cool cool well again we're looking for
Reb but yeah understood um
cool uh everyone have a great week I'm
looking forward to continuing all this
work this is really really fun so talk
to you guys soon um feel free to stay on
and keep chatting if there's more to
talk about
someone
okay cool ciao